翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
all right guys hello everyone I have a little PSA for all of you Windows users
大家好，我有个小提醒要给所有Windows用户
and especially those who use the hibernation feature actively like me
尤其是像我这样经常使用休眠功能的人
I used to be a hater of hibernation and used to shut down my laptop all the time
我曾是个讨厌休眠功能的人，过去总是直接关机
once I switched from shutting down to hibernation a huge problem arose
一旦我从关机切换到了休眠模式，一个巨大的问题就出现了
the laptop started turning on on its own at like 3:00 a.m or something
笔记本在凌晨3点左右突然自己开机了
so apparently Windows actually decides when or when not to turn on your computer
显然，Windows实际上会决定何时开启或关闭你的电脑
when it's hibernated
当它处于休眠状态时
and that setting is enabled by default and you have to change it
该设置默认处于启用状态，必须手动更改
inside the legacy control panel
在旧版控制面板内
it's very treacherous
这非常阴险
so you have to
所以你要
you have to open the legacy control panel inside of here you've got
在这里面打开旧版控制面板
power options as you can see power options
找到电源选项
open that and then you've got
打开你会看到
you got to select your plan in my case it's balanced might be anything else for you
你选的计划，在我这里是“平衡”，对你来说可能是其他方案
and you might want to change multiple plans
你可能需要更改多个计划
if your computer your device uses multiple plans
如果你的电脑或设备使用多个计划
then you have to open advanced power settings right here
你必须在这里打开“更改高级电源设置”
you get a power options window
你会看到电源选项窗口
and in this window you have to select sleep
在这个窗口中，你要选择“睡眠”
and then allow wake timers
然后找到“允许使用唤醒定时器”
there is that setting that turns your device on randomly at night
有个设置会让你的设备在夜间随机开机
and then you have to disable
这里要禁用
you have to disable it completely
要彻底禁用才行
it will be enabled for you by default because Windows is
这个默认启用，因为Windows
Windows doesn't care about what you think
才不在乎你怎么想
so then you hit apply and that's pretty much it
然后点击“应用”，基本上就完成了
and yeah that's the only power plan I've got on my computer here
这就是我电脑上唯一的电源计划了
might be different for you you have to disable it on every case right here
对你来说可能有所不同，你得在每个计划中的这里禁用它
under allow wake timers
在“允许使用唤醒定时器”里
so the main problem with that feature
这个功能的主要问题
is that first of all my laptop is pretty loud it's a gaming laptop you see it's an MSI Vector
首先，我的笔记本电脑声音很大，这是一台游戏本，微星Vector
but more importantly since it's a gaming laptop it heats up and every time
但更重要的是，作为一款游戏笔记本电脑，它会发热，而且每次都会这样
it starts up the fans start spinning a lot
这会让风扇狂转
and if the air is hot it can even damage the LCD on the laptop
如果空气过热，甚至可能损坏笔记本电脑上的液晶显示屏
and I think it's damaged already
而且我觉得它已经坏了
but I'm not sure whether it's because I use hibernation or it's just natural
但我不确定是因为我使用了休眠模式，还是这本来就是自然现象
wear and tear of the laptop
笔记本电脑的磨损
I mean if you if you just look at the screen it's kind of it's kind of damaged
我是说如果你只是看屏幕的话 它有点损坏了
if you take a decent look here see the line
如果你仔细看看这里，就能看到那条线
that's the damage the hot air causes to the LCD
这就是热风对液晶显示屏造成的损害
so you definitely have to turn this Windows feature off because it
所以你必须得关闭这个Windows功能，因为它
原标题：The Windows Feature that Might Damage your Laptop 原作者：Enderman  原视频上传日期：2025年4月23日
it might damage your computer
可能会损坏你的电脑
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
thanks for watching take care
感谢观看，生活愉快
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！